<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Handloom Nepal</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2017-07-09T00:00:00+05:45</updated><entry><title>About US</title><link href="/about-us.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-09T00:00:00+05:45</published><updated>2017-07-09T00:00:00+05:45</updated><author><name>HandloomNepal.com</name></author><id>tag:None,2017-07-09:/about-us.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><content type="html"></content></entry><entry><title>Our Impact</title><link href="/impact.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-09T00:00:00+05:45</published><updated>2017-07-09T00:00:00+05:45</updated><author><name>HandloomNepal.com</name></author><id>tag:None,2017-07-09:/impact.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Background of HWSS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Himalayan Women’s Skills Society is a young and
inspiring non-profit organisation born from the need
to help disadvantages women from an array of
backgrounds. The whole project is very proud to be
self-funded. The women have worked tirelessly
towards getting this project off the ground and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Background of HWSS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Himalayan Women’s Skills Society is a young and
inspiring non-profit organisation born from the need
to help disadvantages women from an array of
backgrounds. The whole project is very proud to be
self-funded. The women have worked tirelessly
towards getting this project off the ground and have
achieved amazing results in a short period of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Products, Handloom Nepal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All products are made from organic materials
including the dye. The highest quality of materials
are used and expertly put together by the women&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Who does the Organisation help?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many women from the small villages surrounding Pokhara do not having adequate education or training to find productive employment, they are left sitting at home feeling isolated, So by training them in weaving, sewing and dying techniques  to making high quality products gives these women a sense of empowerment to improve their own lives and those of their families. It also gives a positive aspect of giving women a sense of community rather than isolation.
Once trained, the women can work from their villages it enables them to take care of the family. Another great advantage of this, is that many are from a farming background and are needed in the fields during planting and harvesting times, this work gives them autonomy to choose their working hours. Not only does it help married women but single women who want an opportunity to have some independence in their lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Women&amp;apos;s Empowerment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Women&amp;apos;s empowerment is a very important issue in Nepal. Historically women’s education was seen as unimportant as there role getting married, children and looking after the family home. This has changed in recent decades. Women themselves want to be educated and actively participate in providing for their family combined with having a career. Often it needs two incomes for the family to provide adequate education for their and sustain good health care provisions. HWSS address these issues in a productive way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Future Plans&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Training programmes are set to be established in rural areas to eliminate the need for women to travel to the city for training. The goal is to train 500 women over the next 5 years and expand in to other areas of Nepal. The training programme is set to include all minority women.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Stories of our Women</title><link href="/our-stories.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-09T00:00:00+05:45</published><updated>2017-07-09T00:00:00+05:45</updated><author><name>HandloomNepal.com</name></author><id>tag:None,2017-07-09:/our-stories.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Every woman in the project has their own unique story but they all have one thing in common, the feeling of empowerment. A way forwards in their lives to benefit not only their family but to help other women improve and progress. These two women mentioned below not only were …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Every woman in the project has their own unique story but they all have one thing in common, the feeling of empowerment. A way forwards in their lives to benefit not only their family but to help other women improve and progress. These two women mentioned below not only were the first to be trained but also helped Monika get the project up and running. They all cut down bamboo to make equipment for the weaving looms, salvaged and reused object that could be used. Both these women had the faith and trust in Monika that they could learn skills to improve their lives; they just didn’t want handouts they wanted a future as all the women in the project do. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read the stories of &lt;a href="/story/bima.html"&gt;Bima&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="/story/kalpana.html"&gt;Kalpana&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Kanya Gurung Trainer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kanaya has been a key figure for training the ladies in weaving skills. She has been training for 15 years. Originally she was a social worker so understands very well the needs of women form these social backgrounds. She has trained over 50 women prior to training with WSDN. Kanya is extremely pleased with the ladies progress and their enthusiasm to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Expectations from the organisation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both ladies love the fact that after school, their children can join them at work and they are in an environment that they are properly cared for while working. Education programmes such as hygiene and good health practices are given on a regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Pokhara Montessori Kinderhome School.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once a year the school children and teachers from Montessori Kinderhome school join together for a fund raising event to support Handloom Nepal. This has a duel aspect. Firstly and obviously Handloom Nepal benefit from the funds raised and secondly the children learn the importance of helping others that need support to help improve their own lives.
A percentage of the product goes to Annapurna self-sustaining home, Batulechaur, Pokhara. To help to educate and provide a stable home for 30 orphans&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Training&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Training is separated into 3 skilful areas; these are all art forms and shows great ability to accomplish.
Dying on average takes 5-6 months; Dying is a very complex and delicate process. Every colour and every shade need precision.
Weaving is a 2 months training period; there are many intricate processes to learn from interpreting the designs to correctly putting the threads on the loom.
Sewing which can take 3-6 months; the machinist need to lean an array of sewing techniques depending on product a design&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Bima</title><link href="/story/bima.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-09T00:00:00+05:45</published><updated>2017-07-09T00:00:00+05:45</updated><author><name>HandloomNepal.com</name></author><id>tag:None,2017-07-09:/story/bima.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Bima started as a weaver, with Monika’s suggestion she became a master dyer which she loves and has a real talent for. Each colour requires a different process. It is a very accurate and technical operation. To consistently produce quality colours is extremely skilful even between shades of the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Bima started as a weaver, with Monika’s suggestion she became a master dyer which she loves and has a real talent for. Each colour requires a different process. It is a very accurate and technical operation. To consistently produce quality colours is extremely skilful even between shades of the same colour takes attention to detail. Bima says the hardest colours are black and red but her favourite, even though very difficult, is coffee.
Despite her situation and many health issues Bima was determined to build a future for here and her family. Coming from a small village roughly 70km from Pokhara, limited education, as there are no constructed roads, transport is very difficult so it involves much walking. As many Nepalese people do especially men feel that the only to support their family is to work abroad. Bima’s husband had an opportunity to work in the Middle-East. For him to do this, meant taking loans from friends and relatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately when he arrived this proved to be a scam that happens to many people from Nepal. He barely made enough money to exist let alone send money for his family or pay loans. It took him 2 years to return to Nepal. Meanwhile Bima was under much stress and obligation to pay the loans and take care of her son. When her husband returned he found work as labourer on a construction site. Bima worked as a cleaner, but both incomes didn’t allow for school fees and general living expenses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to the &lt;a href="/our-stories.html"&gt;Full Story of our company&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Kalpana Chaudhery</title><link href="/story/kalpana.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-09T00:00:00+05:45</published><updated>2017-07-09T00:00:00+05:45</updated><author><name>HandloomNepal.com</name></author><id>tag:None,2017-07-09:/story/kalpana.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Kalpana expertly weaves the threads into magnificent cloths to different specifications in design, colour and lengths ready to be sewn. She is always smiling and has a very happy nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kalpana’s story is not just a story of struggle but also a true love story. Kalpana and her husband …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Kalpana expertly weaves the threads into magnificent cloths to different specifications in design, colour and lengths ready to be sewn. She is always smiling and has a very happy nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kalpana’s story is not just a story of struggle but also a true love story. Kalpana and her husband originated in Chitwan, an area in southern Nepal. As they are both from different casts, neither of their families agreed to their marriage. This proved to be very difficult. In their first year of marriage they were blessed with a baby boy. Unfortunately, Kalana’s husband was unemployed, both families refused to help due to their marriage disagreement. 
With a 1 one year old they decided to move to Pokhara where her husband, after a few months, found work as a metal worker. As their son approached school age it was apparent that there was not enough income to pay school fees and she wanted to contribute to the family.
kalpana left school at the age of 14 and wasn’t encouraged to stay and at the time she didn’t realise the importance of an education While living in the village all there was to do was wonder around and chat with other women, there was no expectation of leaving the village or any significance on having an education. But when faced with the situation of her own child needing to be educated and couldn’t find productive work, she realised this importance. Now she is an expert weaver she is aspiring to become a weaver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to the &lt;a href="/our-stories.html"&gt;Full Story of our company&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>