<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Handloom Nepal - story</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/story.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2017-07-09T00:00:00+05:45</updated><entry><title>Bima</title><link href="/story/bima.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-09T00:00:00+05:45</published><updated>2017-07-09T00:00:00+05:45</updated><author><name>HandloomNepal.com</name></author><id>tag:None,2017-07-09:/story/bima.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Bima started as a weaver, with Monika’s suggestion she became a master dyer which she loves and has a real talent for. Each colour requires a different process. It is a very accurate and technical operation. To consistently produce quality colours is extremely skilful even between shades of the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Bima started as a weaver, with Monika’s suggestion she became a master dyer which she loves and has a real talent for. Each colour requires a different process. It is a very accurate and technical operation. To consistently produce quality colours is extremely skilful even between shades of the same colour takes attention to detail. Bima says the hardest colours are black and red but her favourite, even though very difficult, is coffee.
Despite her situation and many health issues Bima was determined to build a future for here and her family. Coming from a small village roughly 70km from Pokhara, limited education, as there are no constructed roads, transport is very difficult so it involves much walking. As many Nepalese people do especially men feel that the only to support their family is to work abroad. Bima’s husband had an opportunity to work in the Middle-East. For him to do this, meant taking loans from friends and relatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately when he arrived this proved to be a scam that happens to many people from Nepal. He barely made enough money to exist let alone send money for his family or pay loans. It took him 2 years to return to Nepal. Meanwhile Bima was under much stress and obligation to pay the loans and take care of her son. When her husband returned he found work as labourer on a construction site. Bima worked as a cleaner, but both incomes didn’t allow for school fees and general living expenses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to the &lt;a href="/our-stories.html"&gt;Full Story of our company&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Kalpana Chaudhery</title><link href="/story/kalpana.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-09T00:00:00+05:45</published><updated>2017-07-09T00:00:00+05:45</updated><author><name>HandloomNepal.com</name></author><id>tag:None,2017-07-09:/story/kalpana.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Kalpana expertly weaves the threads into magnificent cloths to different specifications in design, colour and lengths ready to be sewn. She is always smiling and has a very happy nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kalpana’s story is not just a story of struggle but also a true love story. Kalpana and her husband …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Kalpana expertly weaves the threads into magnificent cloths to different specifications in design, colour and lengths ready to be sewn. She is always smiling and has a very happy nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kalpana’s story is not just a story of struggle but also a true love story. Kalpana and her husband originated in Chitwan, an area in southern Nepal. As they are both from different casts, neither of their families agreed to their marriage. This proved to be very difficult. In their first year of marriage they were blessed with a baby boy. Unfortunately, Kalana’s husband was unemployed, both families refused to help due to their marriage disagreement. 
With a 1 one year old they decided to move to Pokhara where her husband, after a few months, found work as a metal worker. As their son approached school age it was apparent that there was not enough income to pay school fees and she wanted to contribute to the family.
kalpana left school at the age of 14 and wasn’t encouraged to stay and at the time she didn’t realise the importance of an education While living in the village all there was to do was wonder around and chat with other women, there was no expectation of leaving the village or any significance on having an education. But when faced with the situation of her own child needing to be educated and couldn’t find productive work, she realised this importance. Now she is an expert weaver she is aspiring to become a weaver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to the &lt;a href="/our-stories.html"&gt;Full Story of our company&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>